Nothing is what it seems
The Illusionist is a fantasy, drama, thriller film directed by Neil Burger.
With his eye on a lovely aristocrat, a gifted illusionist named Eisenheim uses
his powers to win her away from her betrothed, a crown prince.
But Eisenheim's scheme creates tumult within the monarchy and
ignites the suspicion of a dogged inspector.
Eisenheim, played by Edward Norton.
Inspector Uhl, played by Paul Giamatti.
Sophie, played by Jessica Biel.
Crown Prince Leopold, played by Rufus Sewell.
Josef Fischer, played by Eddie Marsan.
Young Eisenheim, played by Aaron Taylor-Johnson.
The Illusionist is a 2006 American romantic mystery film written and directed by Neil
Burger and starring Edward Norton, Paul Giamatti, and Jessica Biel.
Based loosely on Steven Millhauser's short story "Eisenheim the Illusionist", it tells the story of Eisenheim, a magician
in turn-of-the-century Vienna, who reunites with his childhood love, a woman far above his social standing.
It also depicts a fictionalized version of the Mayerling incident.
It premiered at the 2006 Sundance Film Festival and opened the 2006 Seattle International Film Festival; it was
distributed in limited release to theaters on August 18, 2006 and expanded nationwide on September 1.
It was a critical and commercial success.
The film explores themes of princess, magic, rivalry, love, vienna, austria.
The tone is emotional and intense.